<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>
    <!-- Animal transport pod crash -->
    <LetterLabelAnimalPodCrash>Animal pod crash</LetterLabelAnimalPodCrash>
    <AnimalPodCrash>A transport pod carrying a {PAWN_kind} called {PAWN_nameDef} is crashing nearby. If it survives the crash, it will be badly wounded.\n\nIf you tend to its wounds, it may decide to stick around.</AnimalPodCrash>
    <AJLabel>Rescued animal joined</AJLabel>
    <AJLetter>The animal you rescued is joining the colony</AJLetter>
    <ADJLabel>Rescued animal didn't join</ADJLabel>
    <ADJLetter>The animal you rescued isn't joining the colony</ADJLetter>
	
    <!-- Traitor -->
    <TraitorLabel>Traitor!</TraitorLabel>
    <Traitor>A colonist named {PAWN_nameDef}, which you have accepted into your ranks, turns out to be an enemy agent from {PAWN_factionName}.

You can capture {PAWN_objective} for recruitment or slavery purposes.</Traitor>

    <!-- Space Battle -->
    <SpaceBattleLabel>Space battle</SpaceBattleLabel>
    <SpaceBattle>Several massive spaceships have engaged in combat in the planet's orbit. Missed shots and debris can impact the ground in the area. This can lead to massive fires.</SpaceBattle>

    <!-- Shuttle Crash -->
    <ShuttleCrashLabel>Shuttle crash</ShuttleCrashLabel>
    <ShuttleCrash>A heavily damaged shuttle is plummeting from the sky and will violently crash nearby.\n\nThe impact will scatter chemfuel and ignite a dangerous fire.\n\nCargo and passengers will be found among the wreckage.\n\nYou must act quickly if you want to rescue the survivors, salvage the cargo, and stop the fire from spreading out of control.</ShuttleCrash>

    <!-- Earthquake -->
    <EarthquakeLabel>Earthquake (magnitude {0})</EarthquakeLabel>
    <EarthquakeDesc>A magnitude {0} earthquake has struck the region!\n\nThe violent shaking has ruptured the ground and caused severe structural damage near the epicenter. Repairs may be required.</EarthquakeDesc>

    <!-- Cargo pods (weapons) -->
    <CPWLabel>Cargo pods (weapons)</CPWLabel>
    <CPW>You have detected a cluster of cargo pods crashing nearby.

Perhaps you'll find something useful in the wreckage.</CPW>

    <!-- Cargo pods (apparel) -->
    <CPALabel>Cargo pods (apparel)</CPALabel>
    <CPA>You have detected a cluster of cargo pods crashing nearby.

Perhaps you'll find something useful in the wreckage.</CPA>

    <!-- Caravan animals wander in -->
    <CAWILabel>Caravan animals wander in</CAWILabel>
    <CAWI>A group of {PAWN_kind}, abandoned or lost, wanders in.

They seem to have belonged to some caravan, as they still carry packs with valuable items. You can collect these items if you tame them or kill them. Otherwise, they will leave the area in a couple of days.</CAWI>

    <!-- Crop sprout -->
    <CSLabel>Wild {0} sprout</CSLabel>
    <CSLetterContent>A grove of wild {0} has sprouted nearby!\n\nIf you wait for the plants to grow, you'll be able to harvest them.</CSLetterContent>
   
    <!-- Battle animals wander in -->
    <BAWILabel>Battle animals wander in</BAWILabel>
    <BAWI>A group of {0}, abandoned or lost, wanders in.

They seem accustomed to human contact and are joining the colony.</BAWI>

    <!-- wild men wander in -->
    <WMWILabel>Wild men wander in</WMWILabel>
    <WMWI>A small, pre-neolithic tribe of wild men wanders in. You can attempt to tame them.</WMWI>

    <!-- Hunting party -->
    <HPLabel>Hunting party</HPLabel>
    <HP>A group of hunters from {0} are passing through the area. They will hunt here for a few hours and then move on.</HP>

    <VEE_Decay>Decaying due to drought.</VEE_Decay>
    <VEE_DroughtGui>Adjusted fertility due to drought: {0}</VEE_DroughtGui>
</LanguageData>