<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>
    <!-- Animal transport pod crash -->
    <VEE_AnimalPodCrashLabel>Animal pod crash</VEE_AnimalPodCrashLabel>
    <VEE_AnimalPodCrashDesc>A transport pod carrying a {PAWN_kind} called {PAWN_nameDef} is crashing nearby. If it survives the crash, it will be badly wounded.\n\nIf you tend to its wounds, it may decide to stick around.</VEE_AnimalPodCrashDesc>
    <VEE_AnimalPodCrashLabel_AceptedJoining>Rescued animal joined</VEE_AnimalPodCrashLabel_AceptedJoining>
    <VEE_AnimalPodCrashDesc_AceptedJoining>The animal you rescued is joining the colony.</VEE_AnimalPodCrashDesc_AceptedJoining>
    <VEE_AnimalPodCrashLabel_RefusedJoining>Rescued animal didn't join</VEE_AnimalPodCrashLabel_RefusedJoining>
    <VEE_AnimalPodCrashDesc_RefusedJoining>The animal you rescued isn't joining the colony.</VEE_AnimalPodCrashDesc_RefusedJoining>
	
    <!-- Traitor -->
    <VEE_TraitorLabel>Traitor: {PAWN_nameDef}</VEE_TraitorLabel>
    <VEE_TraitorDesc>{PAWN_nameDef} has revealed {PAWN_possessive} true colors!\n\n{PAWN_pronoun} was an agent of {Hostile_FactionName} sent to infiltrate your colony. {PAWN_pronoun} has violently turned against you and is now attacking your settlement from the inside. You can subdue or kill {PAWN_objective}!</VEE_TraitorDesc>

    <!-- Orbital ship crash -->
    <VEE_OrbitalCrashLabel>Orbital ship crash</VEE_OrbitalCrashLabel>
    <VEE_OrbitalCrashDesc>A massive orbital ship from {0} has suffered a catastrophic structural failure in orbit directly above your region!\n\nFor the next several hours, massive chunks of hull, volatile engine components, cargo bays, and escape pods will rain down across the area.\n\nKeep your colonists under roofs or carefully dodge the falling debris. Once the shower ends, there will be a lot of resources to salvage, and likely survivors to rescue from the wreckage.</VEE_OrbitalCrashDesc>
	
    <!-- Shuttle Crash -->
    <VEE_ShuttleCrashLabel>Shuttle crash</VEE_ShuttleCrashLabel>
    <VEE_ShuttleCrashDesc>A heavily damaged shuttle is plummeting from the sky and will violently crash nearby.\n\nThe impact will scatter chemfuel and ignite a dangerous fire.\n\nCargo and passengers will be found among the wreckage.\n\nYou must act quickly if you want to rescue the survivors, salvage the cargo, and stop the fire from spreading out of control.</VEE_ShuttleCrashDesc>

    <!-- Earthquake -->
    <VEE_EarthquakeLabel>Earthquake (magnitude {0})</VEE_EarthquakeLabel>
    <VEE_EarthquakeDesc>A magnitude {0} earthquake has struck the region!\n\nThe violent shaking has ruptured the ground and caused severe structural damage near the epicenter. Repairs may be required.</VEE_EarthquakeDesc>

    <!-- Cargo pods (weapons) -->
    <VEE_WeaponCargoPodLabel>Cargo pods (weapon)</VEE_WeaponCargoPodLabel>
    <VEE_WeaponCargoPodDesc>You have detected a cargo pod landing nearby!\n\nIt seems to have carried some weapon, which you can retrieve from the wreckage.</VEE_WeaponCargoPodDesc>

    <!-- Cargo pods (apparel) -->
    <VEE_ApparelCargoPodLabel>Cargo pods (apparel)</VEE_ApparelCargoPodLabel>
    <VEE_ApparelCargoPodDesc>You have detected a cluster of cargo pods landing nearby!\n\nThey seem to contain random apparel, which you can retrieve from the wreckage.</VEE_ApparelCargoPodDesc>

    <!-- Caravan animals wander in -->
    <VEE_CaravanAnimalsWanderLabel>Caravan animals wander in</VEE_CaravanAnimalsWanderLabel>
    <VEE_CaravanAnimalsWanderDesc>A small group of {0} has wandered into the area from the wilderness.\n\nThey appear to be the remnants of a lost or destroyed merchant caravan, as they are burdened with packs full of trading goods.\n\nYou can attempt to tame the animals to claim them and their cargo safely, or you can hunt them down to forcibly take the supplies.</VEE_CaravanAnimalsWanderDesc>

    <!-- Crop sprout -->
    <VEE_CropSproutLabel>Wild {0} sprout</VEE_CropSproutLabel>
    <VEE_CropSproutDesc>A grove of wild {0} has sprouted nearby!\n\nIf you wait for the plants to grow, you'll be able to harvest them.</VEE_CropSproutDesc>
   
    <!-- Battle animals wander in -->
    <VEE_BattleAnimalsWanderLabel>Battle animals wander in</VEE_BattleAnimalsWanderLabel>
    <VEE_BattleAnimalsWanderDesc>A small pack of {0} has wandered into the area from the wilderness.\n\nThey appear to be accustomed to human presence, and have immediately bonded with the colony. \n\nGiven their natural combat capabilities, they will make excellent defensive pets if you assign a handler to train them. Alternatively, if you cannot afford to feed them, they can be slaughtered for food.</VEE_BattleAnimalsWanderDesc>

    <!-- wild men wander in -->
    <VEE_WildMenWanderLabel>Wild men wander in</VEE_WildMenWanderLabel>
    <VEE_WildMenWanderDesc>A small tribe of humans living among wild animals has wandered into the area.\n\nThey are primitive and hungry, and will actively forage for food, which includes eating your crops or raiding unsecured food stockpiles.\n\nYou can attempt to tame them one by one to add them to your colony, arrest them, or deal with them by force if they become too much of a nuisance.</VEE_WildMenWanderDesc>

    <!-- Hunting party -->
    <VEE_HuntingPartyLabel>Hunting party</VEE_HuntingPartyLabel>
    <VEE_HuntingPartyDesc>A small hunting party from {0} has entered the area.\n\nThey have come to hunt the local wildlife for meat and leather. They are peaceful and will not attack your colonists, but they may deplete the local game. Once each hunter bags an animal, they will pack up their kills and leave.</VEE_HuntingPartyDesc>

    <VEE_Decay>Decaying due to drought.</VEE_Decay>
    <VEE_DroughtGui>Adjusted fertility due to drought: {0}</VEE_DroughtGui>
	
	<!--Single manhunter-->
	<VEE_ManhunterSingleArrivalLabel>Manhunter: {0}</VEE_ManhunterSingleArrivalLabel>
	<VEE_ManhunterSingleArrivalDesc>A lone, scaria-infected {0} has entered the area from the wilderness.\n\nIt is entirely rabid and will aggressively attack any human it sees. Keep your colonists inside or draft them to deal with the threat.\n\nBecause of the disease, it will likely die on its own in a few days.</VEE_ManhunterSingleArrivalDesc>
	
	<!--Crashlanded-->
	<VEE_CrashlandedLabel>Crashlanded</VEE_CrashlandedLabel>
	<VEE_CrashlandedDesc> Three escape pods have slammed into the ground nearby. \n\nThree survivors have emerged from the wreckage, looking dazed and lost. They appear to have barely escaped a ship being torn apart in orbit. They will likely rest here to recover from cryptosleep sickness before moving on.</VEE_CrashlandedDesc>
    <VEE_CrashlandedChoiceLabel>Survivors offer to join</VEE_CrashlandedChoiceLabel>
    <VEE_CrashlandedChoiceText>The crashlanded survivors have noticed your colony's struggling numbers. Realizing that survival on the rim is nearly impossible alone, they have offered to join your settlement, bringing their pet and supplies with them.\n\nDo you accept their offer?</VEE_CrashlandedChoiceText>
	<VEE_CrashlandedLeaving>Crashlanding survivors are packing their things and leaving.</VEE_CrashlandedLeaving>

    <!-- Whiteout Refugees -->
    <VEE_WhiteoutRefugees>Desperate refugees</VEE_WhiteoutRefugees>
    <VEE_WhiteoutRefugeesText>A small group of {0} freezing survivors has appeared at the edge of your settlement.\n\nThey are severely hypothermic and starving due to the ongoing whiteout. They are begging you to open your doors and share your warmth and food.\n\nBe warned: they have the wild look of desperate people. If you turn them away to freeze in the snow, they will likely try to take your shelter by force.\n\nWill you accept them?</VEE_WhiteoutRefugeesText>
    <VEE_WhiteoutRefugees_Accepted>The refugees are grateful for your mercy and have joined the colony to recover from their ordeal.</VEE_WhiteoutRefugees_Accepted>
    <VEE_WhiteoutRefugees_Rejected>The refugees have turned on you! Betrayed and desperate, they have sworn to take your shelter by force.\n\nThey are attacking immediately.</VEE_WhiteoutRefugees_Rejected>
</LanguageData>
